Guide to the Douglass Cecil North Papers, 1942-2012 and undated RL.00955
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1953-2012 and undated; 6
  - Writings by Others, 1965-2001 and undated; 5
    - Landa, Janet T. The Economics of the Ethnically-Homogeneous Chinese Middleman Group: A Property-Rights Public-Choice Approach, 1978 (Box 79)
    - Landes, William M. and Solmon, Lewis C. Compulsory Schooling Legislation: An Economic Analysis of Law and Social Change in the 19th Century, 1971 (Box 79)
    - Lau, Lawrence and Frey, Bruno. Ideology, Public Approval, and Government Behavior, 1971 (Box 79)
    - Lee, Dwight R. and Sandler, Todd. On the Optimal Retaliation Against Terrorists, 1988 (Box 79)
    - Lee, Ronald Demos. A Historical Perspective on Economic Aspects of the Population Explosion: The Case of Pre-Industrial England, 1980 (Box 79)
    - Lending to the Prince: Italian Finance and English Kings in Late Medieval Europe, 1988 (Box 79)
    - Lerman, Sarah. Middle Eastern Economic History: Power and Path Dependence since the 12th Century., 2006 (Box 91)
    - Levy-Leboyer, Maurice. La 'New Economic History', 1969 (Box 79)
    - Li, Weisen. The Hayekian Conception of Spontaneous Order and Three path-impulses of Institutional Change. 2001. (Box 91)
    - Liapis, Andrea E. Mergers, Innovations and Schumpeterian Theory: A Study of Pharmaceutical Firms, 2001 (Box 79)
    - Libecap, Gary D. Bureaucratic Opposition to the Assignment of Property Rights: Overgrazing on the Western Range, 1981 (Box 79)
    - Libecap, Gary D. and Wiggins, Steven N. The Influence of Private Contractual Failure on Regulation: The Case of Oil Field Unitization, 1984 (Box 79)
    - Lin, Justin Yifu. An Economic Theory of Institutional Change: Induced and Imposed Change, 1987 (Box 79)
    - Lin, Justin Yifu. The Household Responsibility System Reform in China: A Peasant's Institutional Choice, 1987 (Box 79)
    - Lindbeck, Assar. The International Economic Environment and Industrialization Possibilities in Developing Countries, 1984 (Box 79)
    - Lindbeck, Assar. Redistribution Policy and the Expansion of the Public Sector, 1984 (Box 79)
    - Lindert, Peter H. and Williamson, Jeffrey. English Workers' Living Standards During the Industrial Revolution: A New Look, 1983 (Box 79)
    - Lindert, Peter. Growth, Equality, and History, 1984 (Box 79)
    - Lindert, Peter. Some Consequences of English Population Growth, 1983 (Box 79)
    - Lindert, Peter. Three Centuries of American Inequality, 1975 (Box 79)
    - Lipsey, Robert. A New American Economic History, 1969 (Box 80)
    - Liu, Ruey-Hua. Change of Property Rights and Revenue-Seeking Government: A Study of Taiwan's Land Reform, 1989 (Box 80)
    - Lomborg, Bjorn. Book: Global Crises, Global Solutions., 2005 (Box 91)
    - Lucas, Robert E. On the Mechanics of Economic Development, 1988 (Box 80)
    - Lundgren, Kurt. A Learning Approach to Economic Organization Theory, 1986 (Box 80)
    - Macesich, George. A Monetary Hypothesis and Southern Development, 1964 (Box 80)
    - Macesich, George. Monetary Stock and It's Components in the US, 1834-1860, undated (Box 80)
    - McKinnon, John D. and Kulish, Nicholas. GOP Faces Hard Choices in Tax Benefits., 2001 (Box 91)
    - Maloney, Michael T. and McCormick, R.E. Merger and Capital Structure, 1989 (Box 80)
    - Marczewski, Jean. Buts et méthodes de l'histoire quantitative, 1964 (Box 80)
    - Marczewski, Jean. Quelques observations sur l'article de Monsieur Chaunu, 1964 (Box 80)
    - Margo, Robert A. Disfranchisement, Segregated Schools and the Tiebout Hypothesis, 1985 (Box 80)
    - Margo, Robert A. Educational Achievement in Segregated School Systems: The Effects of 'Separate-But-Equal', 1985 (Box 80)
    - Margo, Robert A. and Villaflor, Georgia. The Antebellum "Surge" in Skill Differentials One More Time: New Evidence, 1985 (Box 80)
    - McClennen, Edward. Rational Choice and Public Policy: A Critical Survey, 1983 (Box 80)
    - McCloskey, Donald N. A Safety-First Model of Scattering, 1975 (Box 80)
    - McCloskey, Donald N. Britain's Loss from Foreign Industrialization: A Provisional Estimate, 1970-1971 (Box 80)
    - McCloskey, Donald N. Did Victorian Britain Fail? 1970-1971 (Box 80)
    - McCloskey, Donald N. and Nash, John. Corn at Interest: The Cost and Extent of Grain Storage in Medieval England, 1980 (Box 80)
    - McCloskey, Donald N. and Sanberg, Lars. From Damnation to Redemption: Judgments on the Late Victorian Entrepreneur, 1971 (Box 80)
    - McCubbins, M.D, Noll, R.G. and Weingast, B.R. Structure and Process; Politics and Policy: Administrative Arrangements and the Political Control of Agencies, 1989 (Box 80)
    - McDonald, John and Snooks, G.D. The Determinants of Rural Income in Domesday England: Evidence from Essex, 1984 (Box 80)
    - McDonald, John and Snooks, G.D. How Artificial were the Tax Assessments in Domesday England? The Case of Essex, 1984 (Box 80)
    - McGuire, Robert and Ohsfeld, Robert. Economic Interest and Voting Patterns at the Constitutional Convention of 1787, undated (Box 80)
    - McKean, Roland. Economics of Ethical and Behavioral Codes, 1974? (Box 80)
    - McPherson, Michael and Winston, Gordon C. The Economics of Academic Tenure, 1983 (Box 80)
    - Means, Gardiner. Corporate Power in the Marketplace, 1982 (Box 80)
    - Meeker, Edward. English Population Decline in the Later Middle Ages, 1968 (Box 80)
    - Memo from Jerry Hume for Trustee Meeting. By Hume, Jerry., 2010 (Box 91)
    - Mercer, Llyd J. The Antebellum Interregional Trade Hypothesis, 1978 (Box 80)
    - Metzler, Allan H. Why Capitalism? Book., 2012 (Box 91)
    - Milgrom, Paul. Bargaining and Influence Costs and the Organization of Economic Activity, 1987 (Box 80)
    - Milgrom, Paul. Memorandum: The Multiplier Effect of Courts on Reputational Enforcement, 1987 (Box 81)
    - Miller, Gary J. Administrative Dilemmas: The Role of Political Leadership, 1982 (Box 81)
    - Miller, Gary J. Managerial Dilemmas: The Role of Political Leadership, 1987 (Box 81)
    - Miller, Gary J. Managing Paradox: The Political economy of Hierarchy, undated (Box 81)
    - Miller, Gary J. Revamping the Federal Trade Commission, 1984 (Box 81)
    - Mitch, David. Exported Growth and Antebellum Economic Development, 1975 (Box 81)
    - Mookherjee, Dilip. Authority, Decentralization and Cooperation in Long-lived Teams, 1984 (Box 81)
    - Mueller, Dennis and Murrell, Peter. Interest Groups and the Size of Government, undated (Box 81)
    - Mukherjee, Sumanta. The Impact of Maternal Employment on Child's Mental Health., 2009 (Box 91)
    - Munger, Michael C. The Costs of Protectionism: Estimates of the Hidden Tax of Trade Restraint, 1983 (Box 81)
    - Murphy, Michael M. From Putting-out to the Factory, undated (Box 81)
    - Musgrave, Richard. Excess Budget: Norms, Hypotheses, and Performance, 1987 (Box 81)
    - The Nature and Function of Social Institutions, undated (Box 81)
    - NBER Reporter 2007, Number 1 (Box 91)
    - Neal, Larry. The Integration and Efficiency of the London and Amsterdam Stock Markets in the 18th Century, 1985 (Box 81)
    - Neal, Larry. A Tale of Two Revolutions: The Effect of Capital Flows, 1789-1823, 1989 (Box 81)
    - Nee, Victor. Bottom-up Economic Development and the Role of the State., 2009-2010 (Box 91)
    - Nelson, Douglas and Silberberg, Eugene. Ideology and Legislator Shirking, 1986 (Box 81)
    - Nelson, Douglas. Capitalism as an Engine of Progress, undated (Box 81)
    - Norman, George. Monopolistic Competition with Outside Goods: Some Thoughts Experiments, 1985 (Box 81)
    - Norton, Seth W. and Tomal, Annette. Religion and Female Educational Attainment., 2006 (Box 91)
    - Nye, John. Ch. 6: The Political Economy of Nineteenth-century Trade., 2004 (Box 91)
    - Nye, John. Economic Growth. Part II. Irreducible Inequality., 2011 (Box 91)
    - Nye, John. War, Wine and Taxes: The Political Economy of Anglo-French Trade 1689-1860., 2005 (Box 91)
    - Olmstead, Alan L. A Reappraisal of the Mechanization of Reaping and Mowing in American Agriculture, 1833-1870, 1974 (Box 82)
    - Olmstead, Alan L. A Savings Bank Depositors in Ante-Bellum New York, 1974 (Box 82)
    - Olmstead, Alan L. and Goldberg, Victor P. Institutional Change and American Economic Growth: A Critique of Davis and North, undated (Box 82)
    - Olson, Mancur. An Agenda for the Study of Institutions, 1984 (Box 82)
    - Olson, Mancur. Property Institutions in Precapitalist Societies, 1980 (Box 82)
    - Olson, Mancur. The Limited Kingdom and the World Market in Wheat and Other Primary Products, 1885-1914, 1974 (Box 82)
    - Olson, Mancur. Some Social and Political Implications of Economic Development, 1965 (Box 82)
    - Olson, Mancur. Prolegomena to a Study of Diseconomies of Scale and Development: An Argument with a Proposal for Further Research, undated (Box 82)
    - Olson, Mancur and Clague, Christopher K. Dissent in Economics: The Convergence of Extremes, 1971 (Box 82)
    - Ostrom, Elinor. Micro-Constitutional Change in a Multi-Constitutional Political System, 1980 (Box 82)
    - Parker, William. A Short History of Productivity Growth in American Agriculture since the Early 19th Century, undated (Box 82)
    - Parker, William. The Historiography of Post-Bellum Southern Economic history with Special Reference to the Organization of Cotton Agriculture, 1978 (Box 82)
    - Parker, William. Economic Developments in North-Western Europe, undated (Box 82)
    - Parker, William. Europe Since 1870: A Birds-eye View, 1983 (Box 82)
    - Parson, Edward A. Social Learning in the Management of Global Environmental Risks: A Review of Theoretical and Applied Works., 1991 (Box 91)
    - Pashigian, B. Peter: The Political Economy of Futures Market Regulation, 1986 (Box 82)
    - Pashigian, B. Peter: Why Have Some Farmers Opposed Futures Markets? 1988 (Box 82)
    - Pascell, Peter. Slavery and Southern Industrial Growth: A Two Sector Approach, undated (Box 82)
    - Peet, Richard J. The Spatial Expansion of Commercial Agriculture in the 19th Century: A von Thuenen Interpretation, 1969 (Box 82)
    - Pejovich, Svetozar. The Relevance of Marx and the Irrelevance of Marxian Revivals in the United States, 1976 (Box 82)
    - Pelikan, Pavel. The Formation of Incentive Mechanisms in Different Economic Systems, 1986 (Box 82)
    - Pelikan, Pavel. The Origin of Predictable Behavior: An optimizer"s Point of View, 1985 (Box 82)
    - Pelikan, Pavel. Choice, Change and Necessity in the Evolution of Forms of Economies., 2001 (Box 91)
    - Penoyer, Ronald J. Reforming Regulation of Hazardous Waste, 1985 (Box 82)
    - Pincus, Jonathan. Government - Chapter 2, undated (Box 82)
    - Piore, Michael and Sabel, Charles. The Industrial Divide, 1984 (Box 82)
    - Pohjola, Matti. Applications of Dynamic Game Theory to Macroeconomics, 1985 (Box 83)
    - Polsby, Nelson W. The Industrialization of the U.S. House of Representatives, 1968 (Box 83)
    - Ponsot, Pierre. En Andalousie occidentale: Les fluctuations de la production du blé sous l'Ancien Régime, 1969 (Box 83)
    - Pope, Clayne. Mortality in 19th Century Households, 1986 (Box 83)
    - Portes, Richard. Finance, Trade and Development: Transatlantic Co-operation in Dealing with the World's Economic Problems, 1985 (Box 83)
    - Posner, Richard A. A Theory of Primitive Society With Special Reference to Law, reprint from 1980 (Box 83)
    - Posner, Richard A. A Theory of Primitive Society With Special Reference to Law, undated (Box 83)
    - Price, Douglas. Careers and Committees in the American Congress: The Problem of Structural Change, undated (Box 83)
    - Professor Douglass North in Zurich., 1994 (Box 91)
    - Pryor, Frederic L. Some Costs and Benefits of Markets: An Empirical Study, 1977 (Box 83)
    - Ransom, Roger B. Social Returns from Public Transport Investment: A Case Study of the Ohio Canal, 1970 (Box 83)
    - Reed, Clyde. Price Data and European Economic History: England 1300-1600, undated (PhD dissertation) (Box 83)
    - Reid Jr, Joseph D. On Navigating the Navigation Acts with Peter D. McClelland, 1969 (Box 83)
    - Riker, William. The Heresthetics of Constitution-making: The Presidency in 1787 With Comments on Determinism and Rational Choice, 1983 (Box 83)
    - Riker, William. "The Lesson of 1787", 1987. (Box 46)
    - Rimsinger, Gaston V. The Legitimation of Protest: A Comparative Study in Labor History, 1960 (Box 83)
    - Roberts, Paul Craig. The Pirenne Thesis: Towards Reformulation, 1964 (Box 83)
    - Rolnick, Arthur J. and Weber, Warren E. Inherent Instability in Banking: The Free Banking Experience, 1985 (Box 83)
    - Rorabaugh, W. J. Apprentices in Early Industrial America, 1983, 3 folders (Box 83)
    - Rosenberg, Nathan. Karl Marx on the Economic Role of Scientific Knowledge, undated (Box 83)
    - Rosenberg, Nathan, Georgescu-Roegen, Nicholas, Ames, E. and Rapp, R.T., Reder, M.W. Writings on Economic Development and Agriculture, 1969-1979, 2 folders (Box 84)
    - Roth, Timothy. Antitrust Policy and the Rationalization of the U.S. Steel Industry, 1985 (Box 84)
    - Rubin, Paul H. Why is the Common Law Efficient? undated (Box 84)
    - Sanderson, Warren C. Economic Theories of Fertility: What Do They Explain, 1974 (Box 84)
    - Sax, Joseph L. Freedom From Wants: Voices From the Wilderness, undated (Box 84)
    - Schapiro, Morton O. Internal Migration in the United States: Evidence from the Early 19th Century, 1982 (Box 84)
    - Schapiro, Morton O. Economic Development and Population Growth: Implications from a Model of U.S. Demographic History, 1985 (Box 84)
    - Schofield, Norman. Social Orders., 2009 (Box 91)
    - Schneider, Hans K. Steel Situation: Consequences of the European Steel Policy After WWII, 1985 (Box 84)
    - Schneider, Friedrich. The Outcome of Social Security Policies: An Institutional Comparison between Austria, Germany and Switzerland, 1987 (Box 84)
    - Schneider, Friedrich. The Influence of Political Institutions on Social Security Policies: A Public Choice View, 1986 (Box 84)
    - Schlager, Edella and Ostrom, Elinor. Common Property, Communal Property, and Natural resources: Some Conceptual Clarifications, 1987 (Box 84)
    - Schofield, Norman. Anarchy Altruism and Cooperation, 1985 (Box 84)
    - Schultz, Theodore W. On Economic History in Extensing Economics, 1975 (Box 84)
    - Schultz, Theodore W. The Family and the Value of Human Time, 1975 (Box 84)
    - Schweitzer, Mary M.: American Economic Policy and the Economic Origins of the American Constitution (working chapter outline"), undated (Box 84)
    - Schweitzer, Mary M.: Property Values and Population Density in Federalist Philadelphia, undated (Box 84)
    - Scott, Anthony. Property Rights and Property Wrongs, 1983 (Box 84)
    - Scully, Gerald W. The Institutional Framework and Economic Development, 1988 (Box 84)
    - Shepherd, James. The Development of Wheat Production in the Pacific Northwest, 1974 (Box 84)
    - Shepherd, James. Staples and 18th Century Canadian Development: A Comparative Study, 1973 (Box 84)
    - Shepherd, James. Commodity Exports From the British North American Colonies to Overseas Areas, 1768-1772: Magnitudes and Patterns of Trade, 1969 (Box 84)
    - Shepherd, William G. Causes of Increased Competition in the U.S. Economy, 1939-1980, 1982 (Box 84)
    - Shepsle, Kenneth A. (Box 85)
    - The Changing Textbook Congress: Congressional Institutions and Behavior in the 1980s, 1988 (Box 85)
    - Cooperation and Institutional Arrangements, 1988 (Box 85)
    - Studying Institutions: Some Lessons From the Rational Choice Approach, 1988 (Box 85)
    - The Positive Theory of Legislative Institutions: An Enrichment of Social Choice and Spatial Models, 1985 (Box 85)
    - Sequence, Interconnection, Reputation, and Repetition: Implications for Cooperation, 1985 (Box 85)
    - Institutional Equilibrium and Equilibrium Institutions, 1983 (Box 85)
    - Shepsle, Kenneth A. and Weingast, Barry R. The Institutional Foundations of Committee Power, 1987 (Box 85)
    - Shepsle, Kenneth A. and Weingast, Barry R. Political Solutions to Market Problems, 1983 (Box 85)
    - Shepsle, Kenneth A. and Weingast, Barry R. Political Solutions to Market Problems, 1984 (Box 85)
    - Shughart, William F. and Tollison, R.D. The Employment Consequences of the Sherman and Clayton Acts, 1984 (Box 85)
    - Silver, Morris. A Non-neo Malthusian Model of English Land Values, Wages, and Grain Yield Before the Black Death, 1983 (Box 85)
    - Smith, Vernon L. Auctions, 1985 (Box 85)
    - Smith, Vernon L. Experimental Methods in Economics, 1985 (Box 85)
    - Smith, Vernon L. Experimental Methods: Reply, 1985 (Box 85)
    - Smith, Vernon L. Hunting and Gathering Economies, 1985 (Box 85)
    - Smith, Vernon L. On Experimental Economics and Rationality., 2002 (Box 91)
    - Sokoff, Kenneth. Productivity Growth in Manufacturing During Early Industrialization: Evidence from the American Northeast, 1820 to 1860, 1985 (Box 85)
    - Solmon, Lewis C. Opportunity Costs and Models of Schooling in the 19th Century, 1969 (Box 85)
    - Solow, Robert S. Economic History and Economics, 1985 May (Box 85)
    - Spence, Michael A. Entry, Capacity, Investment & Oligopolistic Pricing., 1977 (Box 91)
    - Spiller, Pablo T. Politicians, Interest Groups, and Regulators, 1988 Mar. 1 (Box 85)
    - Spufford, Peter. Comparative European Exchange Rates, 1983 (Box 85)
    - Srinivasan, T.N. Neo-Classical Political Economy, the State and Economic Development, undated (Box 85)
    - Solmon, Lewis C. Opportunity Costs and Models of Schooling in the 19th Century, 1970 (Box 85)
    - Stability of a Constitution: An Independent Judiciary in the U.S. Constitution, the 1801-1803 Crisis, undated (Box 85)
    - Steckel, Richard H. and Jensen, Richard A. Determinants of Slave and Crew Mortality in the Atlantic Slave Trade, 1985 (Box 85)
    - Steckel, Richard H. Dimensions and Determinants of Early Childhood Health and Mortality Among American Slaves, 1985 (Box 85)
    - Stewart, Richard B. Four Paradoxes of Liberty, Integrity and Fraternity: The Collective Nature of Environmental Quality and Judicial Review of Administrative Action, 1977 (Box 85)
    - A Theory of Oligopoly, 1964 (Box 91)
    - Stigler, George J. Laissez-Faire: Policy or Circumstance? undated (Box 85)
    - Stillman, Calvin W. On Saving Places, 1977 (Box 85)
    - Stockfisch, J.A. Cost-Benefit-Analysis, Property Rights Specification, and 'Distribution', undated (Box 85)
    - Stockfisch, J.A. The Political Economy of Bureaucracy, 1972 (Box 85)
    - Studenski, Paul The Income of Nations: Theory, Measurement, and Analysis: Past and Present, 1958 (Box 85)
    - Suh, Joon H. 'Voluntary' Export Restraints and Their Effects on Exporters and Consumers: The Case of Footwear Quotas, 1981 (Box 85)
    - Sutch, Richard C. The Profitability of Antebellum Slavery Revisited, 1965 (Box 86)
    - Szreter, Simon. The Right of Registration: Development, Identity, Registration and Social Security – A Historical Perspective., 2006 (Box 91)
    - Taagepera, Rein. Growth-Decline Curves of Empires: Some Regularities, 1984 (proposal) (Box 86)
    - Tan, Elaine S. The Bull is Half the Herd Property Rights and Enclosures in England, 1750-1850., 2000 (Box 91)
    - Transactions Analysis of Office Building Development and Assorted Papers, undated (Box 86)
    - Telsa, Lester. Perceptions and Reality: The Genesis of the Sherman Act, 1985 (Box 86)
    - Tilly, Charles. The Historical Study of Vital Processes, undated (Box 86)
    - Tramontozzi, Paul N. Reforming Water Pollution Regulation, 1985 (Box 86)
    - Troesken, Werner. The Origin of the Sherman Act Reconsidered: A Neo-institutionalism Critique of the Literature, 1989 (Box 86)
    - Tseklis, G. Axelrod Revisited: An Infinite Number of Rounds is not Necessary for Cooperation, 1985 (Box 86)
    - Tullock, Gordon. Industrial Organization and Rent-Seeking in Dictatorships, 1985 (Box 86)
    - Tullock, Gordon. Why Did the Industrial Revolution Occur in England? undated (Box 86)
    - Tullock, Gordon. The Roots of Order, undated (Box 86)
    - Twight, Charlotte. U.S. Regulations of International Trade: A Retrospective Inquiry, 1984 (Box 86)
    - Umbeck, John. Might Makes Rights, 1981 (Box 86)
    - Umbeck, John. Urban Problems in Historical Perspective, undated (Box 86)
    - Van der Wee, Herman. The Long-term Fluctuations in the Commercial Growth of the European Economy, 11th - 18th Century, 1976 (Box 86)
    - Wallis, John J. Why 1933? The Origins and Timing of National Government Growth, 1933-1940, undated (Box 86)
    - Wallis, John J. Why 1933? Governments and States: Understanding Impersonal Rules, Organizations, and the Dynamics of Third-Party Enforcement., 2011 (Box 91)
    - Wallis, North New Book notes, 2009 March (Box 91)
    - Weidenbaum, Murray L. Regulations and the Public Interest, 1983 (Box 86)
    - Weidenbaum, Murray L. Regulatory Reform: A Report Card for the Reagan Administration, 1983 (Box 86)
    - Weidenbaum, Murray L. Cost of Regulation and Benefits of Reform, 1980 (Box 86)
    - Weidenbaum, Murray L. Public Policy: No Longer a Spectator Sport for Business, 1980 (Box 86)
    - Weidenbaum, Murray L. Time to Control Runaway Regulation, 1979 (Box 86)
    - Weidenbaum, Murray L. and Penoyer, R.J. The Next Step in Regulatory Reform: Updating the Statuses, 1983 (Box 86)
    - Weingast, Barry R. Review: Barzel Yoram 'Economics of Property Rights', 1987 (Box 86)
    - Weingast, Barry R. A Rational Choice Perspective on Congressional Norms, 1979 (Box 86)
    - Weingast, Barry R. and Marshall, William J. The Industrial Organization of Congress, 1988 (Box 86)
    - Weingast, Barry R. and Marshall, William J. The Industrial Organization of Congress, 1987 (Box 86)
    - Weingast, Barry R. Notes on Adaptive Efficiency., 2009 (Box 91)
    - Weingast, Barry R. and Shepsle, K.A. and Johnson, C. The Political Economy of Benefits and Costs: A Neoclassical Approach to Distributive Politics, 1981 (Box 86)
    - Weisen, Li. Douglass North's Theory of Institutional Change, 2011 (Box 91)
    - Wiggins, Steven N. The Comparative Advantage of Institutions: Spot Markets, Longterm Contracts, and Firms, 1985 (Box 86)
    - Williamson, Jeffrey G. (Box 87)
    - Immigrant-Inequality Trade-Offs in the Promised Land: Income Distribution and Absorptive Capacity Prior to the Quotas, 1980 ref1958_d40 (Box 87)
    - British Mortality and the Value of Life, 1781-1931, 1982 (Box 87)
    - Butter, Guns, and Crowding-out During the British Industrial Revolution, 1983 (Box 87)
    - Two Centuries of British Income Inequalities: Reconstructing the Past from Tax Assessment Data, 1708-1919, 1979 (Box 87)
    - Was the Industrial Revolution Worth It? Disamenities and Death in 19th Century British Towns, 1981 (Box 87)
    - Williamson, Jeffrey G. and Lindert, P.H. Long Term Trends in American Wealth Inequality, 1977 (Box 87)
    - Williamson, Oliver E. Operationalizing the New Institutional Economics: The Transaction Cost Economics Perspective, 1989 (Box 87)
    - Williamson, Oliver E. Transaction Cost Economics, 1986 (Box 87)
    - Williamson, Oliver E. Organization Form, Residual Claimants, and Corporate Control, 1982 (Box 87)
    - Williamson, Oliver E. The Modern Corporation: Origins, Evolution, Attributes, 1981 (Box 87)
    - Williamson, Oliver E. Transaction-Cost-Economics: The Governance of Contractual Relations, 1970 (Box 87)
    - Williamson, Oliver E. Emergence of the Visible Hand: Implications for Industrial Organization, undated (Box 87)
    - Wildavsky, Aaron. Industrial Policies in American Political Cultures, 1984 (Box 87)
    - Wildavsky, Aaron. A Cultural Theory of Governmental Growth and (Un)balanced Budgets, 1984 (Box 87)
    - Wildman, Louis. Economic Assumptions and the Future of Higher Education, 1976 (Box 87)